索尼影業
索
尼
影
業
哥
倫
比
亞
哥
倫
比
亞
哥
倫
比
亞
索尼公司
想
象
娛樂電影公司
和 想象娛樂電影公司
哥倫比亞電影公司 出品
人類經歷了10萬年
It took the earth's population
a hundred thousand years
和 想像娛樂電影公司
哥倫比亞電影公司 出品
才繁衍出10億人口
to reach a billion people.
聯合發行諾仕達娛樂
在隨後的100年 人口增長到20億
And then just, a hundred more to reach 2 billion.
聯合發行諾仕達娛樂
再翻一番 只花了50年
And only 50 years to double again...
在70年代 人口增至40億
double again to four billion in 1970.
現在 我們快要達到80億了 80億
We're nearly at 8 billion now. ... 8 billion now.
布萊恩·格雷澤
製作
我們正通過延長人均壽命的方式自我毀滅
We are destroying the very means
by which life is extended.
布萊恩·格雷澤
製作
每一次全球性的瘟疫災難都可以被歸咎
the Earth can be traced back...
Every single global ill that plagues
被歸咎於人口的過剩 人口過剩
traced back to human overpopulation... human overpopulation.
為什麼我們還不付諸行動
What didn't we demand any action?
我們大量砍伐 傾倒垃
圾 揮霍消費 肆意破壞
we clear cut, we dump,
we consume, we destroy.
朗·霍華德 作品
地球上半數的動物物種業已消亡
Half the animal species on earth have vanished
在過去40年裡被滅絕 40年
vanished for the last 40 years... 40 years.
湯姆·漢克斯
我們仍在侵略自然環境
and still we keep attacking
our own environment!
湯姆·漢克斯
非到大難臨頭 才
得深刻教訓 ... 留心關注
it doesn't take a catastrophe to learn
our lesson... to get our attention
唯有痛苦方可改變行為
Nothing changes behaviour like pain.
但丁密碼
或許只有痛苦 才能拯救我們
Maybe pain can save us.
但丁密碼
有一個開關
There is a switch,
菲麗希緹·瓊斯
若你打開
if you throw it,
伊爾凡·可汗
地球上半數人口會死亡
half the people on earth will die.
奧馬·希
但反之 人類將在一百年內滅絕
But if you don't, the human race will
be extinct in a hundred years.
本·福斯特
希德絲·巴比特·科努德森
你會怎麼做
What would you do?
安娜·烏拉魯
人類就像人體內的癌症
Mankind is the cancer in its own body.
艾達·達文什
保羅·裡特
你有拯救芸芸眾生的切膚博愛嗎
Do you love humanity enough to save it?
選角導演
尼娜·金
為防萬一 他們捉住我
In case, they find me,
服裝設計
朱利安·戴
我給你留下了一串指引
I left you a path.
視覺特效
喬迪·約翰遜
但它是最艱險的征程
The hardest one yet.
坎坷盡頭 橫亙煉獄
Inferno will be at the end
音樂
漢斯·季默
你是我的應急計劃
You are my contingency plan.
編劇
丹·布朗
大衛·凱普
你是人類最後的希望
You are humanity's final hope.
藝術指導
彼得·威漢姆
請確保地獄的降臨
Make sure Inferno is unleashed.
尋找 就尋見
尋找 就尋見- 聖經 馬太福音 第七章 第七節
Seek and find
攝影導演
薩爾瓦托雷·托迪諾
佛羅倫薩巴迪亞教堂 佛羅倫薩 意大利
Badia Fiorentina (Church), Florence, Italy
執行製片人
大衛·豪斯霍爾特 丹·布朗
製作人
威廉·M·康納
安娜·選
本·魏斯布論
追了一路
A long road.
卻跑來這裡
but here we are.
製作人
布萊恩·格雷澤
朗·霍華德
相比美國人 我更棒些
Better me, than the Americans.
由 丹·布朗 小
說
改
編
接下來你要向我坦白 它在哪裡
You're going to want to tell me where it is.
沒錯 布沙爾先生
Yes, Mr. Bouchard.
劇本
大衛·凱普
我知道我會的
I know I will.
告訴他們
Tell them,
人類是災 地獄為解
"Humanity is the disease, Inferno is the cure."
導演
朗·霍華德
叛徒
Traitor!
受難吧 罪人們 為汝之孽付出代價
Suffer, you sinners. Pay for your sins.
為汝之孽付出代價
Pay for your sins.
受難吧 罪人們 為汝之孽付出代價
Suffer, you sinners. Pay for your sins.
丟魂失魄
Ruin of souls...
- 請稍等- 怎麼回事．．．
- One moment, please - What is going ...
- 發生了什麼- 布魯克斯醫生
- What is happening - Dr. Brooks
拋棄所有的希望
Abadon all hope
所有希望
All hope ...
蘭登先生 我是布魯克斯醫生
Mr. Langdon, I'm Dr. Brooks.
我會做些檢查 不必擔心
I'm going to do a few checks, nothing to worry about.
咱們把它扔掉 好嗎
Let's get rid of this, shall we?
您知道今天是周幾嗎
Do you know what day of the week it is?
週六
Saturday.
今天週一 6月28號
It's Monday, 28th of June.
週一 6月28號
Monday, 28th of June.
您知道我們在哪兒嗎
Do you know where we are?
波士頓
Boston.
麻省總醫院
Massachusetts General (Hospital)
您最後能記起的事情是什麼
And what's the last thing you can remember?
我 呃 我在校園裡
I uh... I was on campus.
一切都好模糊 我看不清楚
Everything is blur. It's out of focus.
我是不是遇到了什麼意外
Was I in some kind of an accident?
我們會弄清楚的
We'll get to that.
您有沒有人需要幫忙通知的
Is there someone we should call for you?
沒
No.
您的妻子 家人
Your Wife? Family?
不 不 我沒結婚
No. No. I'm not married.
蘭登教授 你的頭部受創
Professor Langdon, you're suffering from a head trauma.
您似乎有輕微的逆行性失憶
You appeared to have a mild retrograde amnesia
我們做了個CT掃瞄 沒有發現顱內出血
We've done a CT scan, there's no
evidence of intracranial bleeding.
一切都挺好 會恢復的
Which is very reassuring. Non-terminal.
試著放鬆下來
Just try to relax.
神經系統方面 看樣子沒問題
Neurologically, you seem to be fine.
您的記憶會在隨後幾天恢復
Your memory will return over the next several days.
那麼我們 ... 我們就安心靜養吧
So we'll... we'll wait and watch.
能麻煩你關下燈嗎
Could you turn off the lights please.
沒問題
Of course.
若是頭部創傷嚴重 導致腦挫裂傷 那...
If the head trauma was bad enough to
cause a cerebral contusion, then...
麻煩你 ... 麻煩你關下燈好嗎
Could you please ... Could
you please turn off the lights?
我在 ... 佛羅倫薩 ... 來幹什麼
What am I... doing... in Florence?
那是個大教堂 是佛羅倫薩舊宮 對嗎
That's a Duomo. That's
the Palazzo Vecchio, isn't it?
對的
Yes.
怎麼 ... 我怎麼來這兒的
How... How did I get here?
3小時前 你頭部帶傷 跑來我們的急診室
You came to our emergency room
3 hours ago with a head wound.
我 ... 我是不是還有位女伴
Was I... Was I with a woman?
沒 一位出租車司機送您來的
No, a cab driver brought you in.
沒拿錢包 沒有手機 沒帶身份證
No wallet. No phone. No ID.
你怎麼知道我名字
How do you know my name?
咱倆見過
We've met.
我在倫敦帝國學院聽過你的演講後面還聊了下
I saw you lecture at the Church in Imperial College London, we spoke afterwards,
您待我很親切
you were very nice to me.
我們見過
We've met.
抱歉 那樣講不大恰當
Sorry, that's not quite fair.
那時候我9歲
I was nine at that time.
慢著 9... 9歲
Wait. Nine-nine years old?
我那時對拼圖遊戲很入迷
I was crazy about puzzles.
我也喜歡您的書
And I like your books.
也許不是"失落的表意文字語言"而是其他的
Maybe not "Lost language of Ideograms"
but the others.
好吧
Okay.
我全看了
I read them all.
古怪的小年輕
A weird kid.
的確如此
I was actually.
我剛剛講得很大聲嗎
Did I say that out loud?
是的
You did.
非常抱歉
Very sorry.
憲兵
寶馬
蘭登教授您的頭疼症狀一開始會比較強烈
Professor Langdon, your headaches
are going to be intense initially.
您也可能還會有噁心 糊塗 頭昏等情況
And you can also expect nausea, confusion and dizziness.
前台來的電話
That was the front desk.
警察來了 要見您
The police are here to see you.
我 為什麼
Me, why?
在與他們交流之前 蘭登教授 您應該瞭解一下您的真實情況
Before you talk to them, Professor Langdon, you should know the facts of your case.
您頭部的創傷並非事故所致
Your head wound was not caused by an accident.
而是槍擊造成的
It was the result of a gunshot.
一枚子彈擦過您頭骨頂端 您很可能還狠狠地摔了下來
A bullet grazed the top of your skull and you most likely took a bad fall
這是導致腦震盪的原因
which is what caused the concussion.
如果子彈再往裡一英吋
If the bullet had been an inch to the side,
它就真的要命了
it could have killed you.
快點 快點兒
Come on, Come on
這邊 這邊 快
This way. This way, come on.
出租車
Taxi.
進來
Get in.
啥 你們喝醉了嗎
What, are you drunk?
怎麼回事
What happened?
快走
Let's go!
加速 開快點
Step on it. Floor it!
- 出了啥事
- 我不知道
- What's going on? - I don't know
接下來會比較疼
This is gonna hurt.
沒關係
It's okay. It's okay.
羅伯特
Robert.
尋找 就尋見
Seek and find.
佛羅倫薩 意大利
尋找 就必尋見
Seek and find.Florence, Italy 4:52 AM
凌晨 4:52
這兒是我的住處
This is my apartment.
你仍在佛羅倫薩
You're still in Florence.
我要打電話叫警察
I'm going to call the police.
等會 那個女警剛剛才試著殺掉咱們
Wait. That policewoman just tried to kill us.
好的
Okay.
那我們打給美國領事館 如果你沒意見的話
We will call the U.S. Consulate instead if you like.
先慢著 讓我 ... 讓我歇會
Just... wait. Just give me... give me a minute.
- 整理下情況
- 為什麼會有人射殺你
- Get a hold on things - Why was someone shooting at you?
我不知道
I don't know.
還有 你進急診室時
Also, when you came into ER,
你在反覆喃喃些什麼
you were mumbling something over and over.
非常抱 ... 非常抱歉
Very sorr... Very sorry.
非常抱歉
Very sorry.
你知道你當時為什麼要講這些嗎
Do you have any idea why you would be saying this?
- 不知道- 為什麼有人要射殺你
- No. - Why was someone shooting at you?
你可以繼續對我追問這些 女士
You can keep asking me these questions, lady.
但我也不知道答案是什麼
But I'm not going to know these answers!
我叫西恩娜
My name is Sienna.
對不起
I'm sorry.
你好
Hello.
Hi.
你剛剛問了很多問題
You just asked a lot of questions.
沒錯 我感覺我現在非常玻璃心
Yeah, I'm feeling a tad vulnerable right now.
我現在身旁待著一個正被追殺的人
I'm with someone other people want to shoot at!
對不起
I'm sorry.
這些問題很重要
Questions are important.
我希望你能記起來
And I hope you recover.
我可以再要 ... 一杯
Can I ask you for a... cup of a...
那啥 棕色的 熱的
What? It's brown and it's... hot.
人們早上喝來補充能量的 呃
People drink it in the morning for energy. Uh...
茶
Tea.
茶 不 另一種
Tea. No. The other one.
- 咖啡- 咖啡
- Coffee. - Coffee.
我能要一杯咖啡嗎
Could I have a cup of coffee?
當然
Sure.
謝謝
Thank you.
你整理得很好
You are very organized.
我喜歡井井有條的樣子
I like things tidy.
謝謝你在醫院裡的幫助
Thank you for helping me in the hospital.
非常勇敢
That was very courageous.
本能反應罷了
It's just reflexes.
"非常抱歉"
"Very sorry".
非常...
Very...
抱歉
sorry
我想我有些幻覺
I feel I'm having visions.
那是因為頭部創傷
It's the head trauma.
一段時間內 你會無法依賴自己的意識
You won't be able to trust your own thoughts for a while.
我看見一個瘟疫面具
I saw a plague mask.
有點像中世紀醫生 ... 在黑死病肆虐時期的形象
It's the kind the medieval doctors wore in... during the Black death.
你講過類似的
You said something about that.
你在出租車裡講過 不過大多不連貫
You were talking in the cab it was mostly incoherent but...
但我的確聽到"面具"兩字
But I did hear the word mask.
還有嗎
Anything else?
還有軀體 血液 火焰 ...
The bodies, the blood and fire and...
... 和地獄
... hell.
還有位女士
And there's a woman.
那位女士 她看著 ...
The woman, she seemed...
尋找 就必尋見
Seek and find
呃 看著很嚇人
Uh. Well, seemed so dangerous.
不 你肯定有人我們可以聯繫一下的
No, you got to have somebody we should call.
我有嗎 為什麼
I do? Why?
我的 ... 我有沒有
My wat... Was I wearing
在去醫院的時候戴著塊手錶
my watch when I was brought to the hospital?
沒
No.
你沒戴表
You weren't wearing a watch.
它對我意義重大 是我父母送的
It's important to me. It was a gift from my parents.
嘿 你該朝前看 忘掉它
Look, you should go ahead and clean up.
你的衣服沾血了 不過我想我有適合你穿的
Your clothes are covered in blood but I think I got something that might fit you.
你穿上後 我們就打電話給警方 行嗎
Once you get dressed, we'll call the police, okay?
不 不 領事館
No. No. The Consulate.
行 領事館
Right. The Consulate.
咖啡
Coffee.
入讀倫敦國王學院的12歲神童
Prodidy, 12, to attend King's College
我祈禱你一切安好
伊格納奇奧·布索尼
伊格納奇奧
Ignazio?
羅伯特，
伊格納奇奧·布索尼致
抱歉無法依計劃與你會面.
他們現在找上我了.
我們所盜之物藏於安全之所， 本人亦是.
天堂  25號.
我祈禱你一切安好
抱歉無法依計劃與你會面
I'm sorry I couldn't meet as planned.
他們現在找上我了
Now they're after me too.
我們所竊之物
What we stole
藏於安全之所 本人亦是
... is safely hidden, as am I.
我們所竊之物
"What we stole"?
天堂 25
Paradise Twenty-five.
伊格納奇奧
Ignazio.
你的東西我都放浴室了
I've left your things in the bathroom.
試試這些
Try these.
這是誰的
Whose are they?
一位朋友的
A friend.
他住這嗎
Does he live here?
有時候
Sometimes.
噢 有時候 蛤
Oh. Sometimes, huh.
你有點粗魯了
You're being rude.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
抱歉 我不是那種人
I'm sorry, I'm not like this.
那可說不准
You kind of are.
我在舊夾克裡發現了這個
I found this in my old jacket.
這是生物試管
It's a biotube.
用於運輸危險物質
They're used for transporting dangerous substances.
你用來幹嘛
What are you doing with it?
我不知道
I have no idea.
這是個高端裝置
It's a high end unit.
官方製造的
Government issue.
這兒是指紋識別 萬一遺失或被盜後的安保措施
It's called thumbprint recognition.Security in case it's lost or stolen.
這種管子只能由某位特定人物開啟
Tubes like this can only be opened by a specified individual.
這個 人肯定不是我
Well, it sure hell isn't me.
- 那你為什麼帶著它- 我不知道
- Then why do you have it? - I don't know.
我去查一下領事館的號碼
I'm getting the number for the Consulate.
請不要 等等
No, please. Wait.
我等過了 這樣做不合適
I have waited. This isn't right.
你怎麼會有它 你從哪兒弄的
Why do you have it? Where did you get it?
瞧 有個簡單的法子
Look, there is a simple way
可以弄清楚它究竟是不是我的
to find out if this thing belongs to me.
我去用拇指打開它 或者嘗試失敗
Then my thumb will open it or it won't.
打開它 你瘋了嗎
Open it, are you insane?
如果它是病毒藥劑 我打開後它會被釋放嗎
If it's a viral agent, will it be released if I opened it?
不會
No.
不會的 內部會有一層密封甚至可能兩層
No, there'll be an inner seal maybe even two.
把我自己交給別人之前 我想知道這是啥玩意
Before I put myself in anyone's hands I want to know what this thing is.
嗯 還有我捲進了什麼事件裡面
Uh, and what I'm involved with.
一切都合情合理 對嗎
That make sense, doesn't it?
對的
Yes.
那麼 達成一致
So, we agree.
我們把它打開
We're opening it.
好吧 那說明它就是我的
Well, that explains that it is mine.
一個象牙製成的密封圓柱體
This is a cylinder seal made of ivory.
不對
No.
這是骨頭
It's bone.
人骨
Human.
三頭帶角的撒旦 正在吞噬三個人
Three-headed, man eating Satan.
中世紀時的常見形象
A common image from the Middle Ages
這與黑死病密切相連
associated with the Black Plague.
三張血盆大口
The 3 gnashing mouths are symbolic of
正是這瘟疫在人群中肆虐的象徵
how effectively the plague ate through the population.
而你卻記不起"咖啡"該怎麼講
Yet you can't remember the word for coffee.
它在一定程度上解釋了我的幻覺
It explains my visions, sort of.
- 你聽見了嗎- 嗯
- Do you hear that? - Mm-mm.
可能是個法拉第指示器
This could be a Faraday pointer.
為 為什麼會這樣 嗯
So why-why this, huh?
波提切利的畫作
It's Botticelli.
這是他的"地獄圖"
It's his map of hell.
詳細描繪了但丁筆下的地獄
但丁 - 神曲·地獄篇
He painted it as an illustration of Dante's Inferno.
年輕的時候我學習過但丁的作品
I studied Dante when I was younger.
也許是在幼兒園裡
Probably in kindergarden.
當時挺著迷的
I was a bit obsessed.
但丁定義了現代社會中的地獄概念
Dante defined our modern conception of hell.
我們對地獄的看法700年前就定型了
Our vision of it hasn't changed since he defined it 700 years ago.
波提切利畫了出來 但 ... 但丁是眾所周知的締造者
Botticelli drew it but... Dante created hell as we know it.
這也是我的幻覺所見
This is what I have been seeing.
圖為地獄第八層：
欺詐的獻詐者
酷刑拷問
Torment.
罪孽亡魂
欺詐的挑撥離間者 圖為地獄第八層：
Sinners.
販子被打上烙印
圖為地獄第八層： 欺詐的神棍
Branding the mongers.
說謊者全身發疹
圖為地獄第八層：欺詐的作偽者
Liars, covered with rashes.
圖為地獄第八層：欺詐的占卜者
預言者頭部倒反
Soothsayers with their heads turned backwards.
- 蛇- 對偷竊的刑罰
圖為地獄第八層：欺詐的盜賊
- Serpents. - The punishment for thievery.
受難吧 罪人們 為汝之孽付出代價
Suffer, you sinners. Pay for your sins.
那麼你對為何擁有此物一無所知
So you have no idea why you have this?
我想現在或許該聯繫領事館了
I think maybe we call the consulate now.
對
Right.
蘭登教授
Professor Langdon?
你好 是的 是我
Hello, yes. Speaking.
謝天謝地你還活著 我們一直在找你
Thank heavens you're alive. We've been looking for you.
是嗎
You have?
你還帶著嗎
Are you still in possession?
蘭登先生 管子還在嗎
Mr. Langdon, do you have the tube?
- 是的- 你的位置是
- Yes. - Where are you located?
教授 我們找不著你 就無法幫你
Professor, we can't help you if we can't find you.
如果那是領事館 他們又如何知情
If that's the consulate, how do they know?
因為他們本就知道
Because they know.
領事館
來電
怎麼辦
What do we do?
告訴他們你在那兒
Tell them you're over there.
家庭旅館
- 你好- 教授剛才斷線了
- Hello. - Professor, we were cut off.
是的 抱歉
Yes, sorry.
你在哪兒
Where are you located?
我在一家旅館裡 佛羅倫薩家庭旅館
I'm at a hotel, Pensione la Fiorentina.
待在房間裡 我們的人馬上就到
Stay in your room. We're sending someone now.
我在這等著 39號房
I'll wait here, room 39.
好的 我們就等著 看他們派誰來
Okay. We wait and see who they send.
世界衛生組織
流動指揮車
清 晨 6:37
蘭登通過佛羅倫薩的
Langdon accessed his email account from
an unmasked IP address here in Florence
一個未加密IP登錄了郵箱帳號
- 什麼時候- ７分鐘前
- When? - 7 minutes ago.
維亞多樂羅莎大道12號3C公寓
Via Dolorosa, number 12, apartment 3C.
維亞多樂羅莎大道 要多久
Via Dolorosa, how long?
12分鐘
12 minutes.
行動 拿回指示器 還有蘭登
Go! I want that pointer back and I want Langdon.
無論如何 把他抓回來
Whatever it takes, let's get him.
走 走 走 走 就現在
Go, go, go, go, now!
看這個 好奇怪
Look at this. This is odd.
這塊區域是但丁的地獄第八層
This area here is Dante's 8th level of hell.
叫Malebolge 意為邪惡之囊
It's called the Malebolge, means evil ditches.
一共有十種罪惡
There's ten.
這兒的字母"R" 原畫中並沒有
This letter "R" here, is not in the original painting.
是後加的
It's been added.
還有一個
There's another one.
- 哪裡- 有個〞Ｅ〞
- Where? - An "E".
被惡魔鞭笞的誘姦者
On seducers whipped by demons.
- 面頰上有個〞Ｃ〞的人- 是污吏
- There's a "C" on the cheek of a... - A grafter.
- 貪污犯
- 困在滿池沸騰瀝青中的騙子
- ... a grafter. - A conman trapped in a pool of boiling tar.
- 〞Ｖ〞〞Ｒ〞
- 啊那兒
- A "V", "R".- Ah, there.
- 〞Ｔ〞
- 那兒那兒〞Ａ〞
- "T". - There, there, "A".
那是什麼
What is that.
一段文字 那是英文嗎
That's text. Is that in English?
唯有透過死亡之眼才能瞥見真相
透過死亡之眼才能瞥見真相
佐布裡斯特
ZOBRIST.
貝特朗·佐布裡斯特
億萬富翁，偉大的生物工程師
...貝特朗·佐布裡斯特，美國億
萬富翁，這一代偉大的生物
工程思想家，因對人口過剩
問題觀點激進而臭名昭著。
其他人也在搜索
貝特朗·佐布裡斯特
Bertrand Zobrist.
- 美國的億萬富翁那一定很棒- 蛤
- American billionaire, that must be nice. - Hm.
貝特朗·佐布裡斯特
億萬富翁，偉大的生物工程師
...貝特朗·佐布裡斯特，美國億
萬富翁，這一代偉大的生物
工程思想家，因對人口過剩
問題觀點激進而臭名昭著。
其他人也在搜索
生物工程師
Bioengineer
因激進觀點而聲名狼藉
Notorious for radical views.
他在這兒
Here he is.
人類經歷了10萬年
It took the earth's population a hundred thousand years
才繁衍出10億人口
to reach a billion people.
在隨後的100年 人口增長到20億
And then just a hundred more to reach two billion.
再翻一番只花了50年 70年代人口40億
And only fifty years to double again to four billion people in 1970.
現在 我們快有80億了
We're nearly at eight billion now.
巴特利特以燒杯為例
Bartlett used the example of a beaker.
巴特利特-英國化學家
英國化學家,巴特利特--
闡述燒杯中的細菌在一定的溫度下
成倍增加，貝特朗·佐布裡斯特-
則以這種化學效應來影射人類人口
過剩，腐化墮落及十大罪惡增長速
度就像燒杯中的細菌一樣衍生和發
展，並呼籲全世界各國政府立即采
取措施制止。其真實面目是一個反
人類，反社會的殉道者。（反正都
是杜撰）
巴特利特的燒杯理論
內有一個細菌細胞
With a single bacterium.
每分鐘分裂一次 數目翻倍
One that divides and doubles every minute.
如果在11點整將第一個細菌細胞置於杯中
If you placed the first bacterium into the beaker at 11 o'clock.
每分鐘一個變成兩個
（成幾何級數增長）
12點整時杯就全滿了
and it's completely full by 12.
每分鐘一個變成兩個
（成幾何級數增長）
在何時燒杯還是半滿的呢
At what time is the beaker still only half full?
11:59
那就是現在的我們
That's what time it is for us.
未來40年內 會有320億人口 在生死線上掙扎
In 40 years, 32 billion people... will fight to survive.
還沒失敗
No fail.
距離午夜 我們還差一分鐘
We're a minute to midnight.
每一次全球性的瘟疫災難都可以被歸咎於人口的過剩
Every single global ill that plagues the Earth can be traced back to human overpopulation.
而嚴肅的生育控制手段卻毫無施行可能
But serious birth control measures they don't stand a chance.
聳人聽聞 違背個人權利
Outrageous! Violation of my rights!
侵犯個人隱私 別來好為人師
Invasion of my privacy! Don't tell me what to do!
然而 我們仍在侵略自然環境
But still we keep attacking our own environment!
地球歷史上已經有過5次物種大滅絕
They have been 5 major extinctions in the earth's history.
貝特朗·佐布裡斯特
人口過剩
生物工程
剩
我們若不立即採取大膽行動
Unless we take bold immediate action
第六次就會輪到我們頭上
the sixth extinction will be our own.
距離午夜 我們還差一分鐘
We're a minute to midnight.
貝特朗·佐布裡斯特
人口過剩
生物工程
看起來他有挺多擁護者
Looks like he's got a lot of followers.
嗯 來自全球各地 五湖四海
Yeah, from all over the world.
他挺令人信服的
He is compelling.
貝特朗
佐布裡斯特
衛報
提要
繼續搜索美國億萬富翁
在佐布裡斯特消失的兩年時間裡 部分當局人員擔心
The 2 year disappearance during which some authorities feared Zobrist
他可能研發了一種有害於免疫能力底下群體的病毒病原體
may have designed an opportunistic viral pathogen.
他製造了一種瘟疫病毒
He created a plague.
但 為什麼是但丁
But, why Dante?
為什麼是這幅"地獄圖"
Why this map of hell?
這是拼圖遊戲 或者挑戰嗎
Is this supposed to be a puzzle or a challenge?
也可能是遺書
Or a suicide note.
3天前他自殺了
He killed himself 3 days ago.
等級
The levels.
罪惡等級是亂序的 這是困擾我的地方
The levels are out of order, that's what's been bothering me.
地獄這一層的次序被重新分佈了
This circles of hell had been rearranged.
跟醫院的女子是同一人
It's the same woman from the hospital.
我們不能待在這 肯定不能相信領事館了
We can't stay here. We certainly can't trust the Consulate.
字母像佈置時那樣被加密 也不對
The letters are encrypted as committers, that's not right.
如果病毒真的存在 你知道有多少政府想要弄到手嗎
If the plague exist, do you know how many governments would want it?
神棍 猜不出
Clerical profiteers, not there.
- 他們都會做些什麼來得到這些
- 挑撥離間者不是
- What they would do to get it. - Someone who discord dead, no.
生化武器
A biological weapon.
這些字母
The letters.
他把每種罪行都加上了字母 然後打亂次序
He has assigned a letter to each sin and then changed their order.
他設了一個字謎
He's made an anagram.
對了 字謎
Yes. Anagram.
走 我知道另一條路能出去
Let's go. I know another way out.
如果你帶了手機 最好留在這兒
If you have phoned, best leave it here.
可能會被追蹤
They might track it.
手機 衣服都不是我自個的
The phone? I'm not even wearing my own clothes.
很好 走吧
Good. Let's go.
羅伯特·蘭登 世界衛生組織
Robert Langdon! World Health Organization! (WHO)
V, R, O.
我得重排這些字母 Over Code
I got to rearrange these letters, CATROVACER.
Covered Cat
天 這種東西我以前挺上手的
God. I used to be good at this.
Cerca trova.
意大利語 意為"尋找"和"發現"
It's Italian. It means "seek" and "find".
Cerca trova 好的
Cerca trova. Yes!
我知道我為什麼會在佛羅倫薩了
I know why I am in Florence.
世界衛生組織已經抵達 待命
World Health Organization has landed, standby.
注意
Be advised.
來自巴黎的布沙爾探員已經到場
Agent Bouchard, from the Paris office is already here.
世界衛生組織 告訴我最新情況
W.H.O, Bring me up to speed.
布沙爾已經上去了
Bouchard is up there now.
- 我們去哪
- 舊宮波波利花園附近
- Where are we going? - The Palazzo Vecchio, near the Boboli Gardens.
沒有發現他
There's no sign of him.
布沙爾說蘭登已經走了 指示器也不在
Bouchard says Langdon is gone and so is the pointer.
這可不行
Well, I need better.
你 你 你們全部都要表現得更好
I need better from you, from you, from all of us.
更像樣
Better!
還要更迅速 更敏捷 別相信任何人
Work faster. Work smarter. Don't trust anyone.
大家加油吧
Let's do that.
- 去吧
- 是
- Let's go. - Yes.
情報看樣子已經沒用了
The information seems to be obsolete.
- 不要透露給秘書長明白嗎
- 明白
- Do not say anything to the secretary general. - OK
- 身份　- 瓦任莎
- Identification. - Vayentha.
- 繼續- 我要跟教務長通話
- Go ahead. - I need to speak to the provost.
稍等
Hold on.
"門達西烏姆號"遊艇
Adriatic Sea 7:12 AMThe Mendacium.
亞得裡亞海
清晨 7:12
那麼WHO在追蹤蘭登這事上先你一步瓦任莎
So, the WHO beat you to Mr. Langdon, Vayentha.
教務長可不喜歡這樣
The provost isn't going to like that.
我知道 他想要清掉我了
I know. He's going to want to liquidate.
告訴他這兒不是柏林
Tell him this isn't Berlin.
他敢試 我就找上門
He tries anything and I will find him.
一小時內再試一遍 然後聯繫我們
Try to reacquire and make contact in 60 minutes.
你有沒有在聽 我不是一次性用品
Did you hear me? I am not disposable.
瓦任莎 搶先將法拉第指示器弄到手
Vayentha, get the Faraday pointer before the government does.
靠
Shit.
- 西姆斯先生 - 嗯
- Mr. Sims. - Mm.
事情出了點偏差
There's been a deviation.
聽到這個真遺憾
Sorry to hear that.
- 什麼行動- 佛羅倫薩
- What operation? - Florence.
我們的新外勤似乎有點隨性亂來了
Our new players seemed to have gone off script.
真夠業餘
How unprofessional.
現在WHO已經取代了我們的位置
And now the WHO has overtaken our position.
告訴瓦任莎 如果她還在乎這份工作
Tell Vayentha, if she values her position
她就該除掉蘭登
she will remove Langdon.
毀屍滅跡
Body not found.
或者再妙點 攔路搶劫
Or better yet, a mugging gone awry.
來上一刀 我覺得 現金劫走 錢包留下
A blade, I think. Cash gone, wallet remains.
趕緊確認下 然後繼續 繼續 繼續
Let's have a quick identification and move on. Move on, move on.
蘭登教授已經脫離監視了
Professor Langdon is out of frame.
- 還帶著管子嗎- 是的
- And in possession of the tube? - Yes.
他帶著法拉第指示器
He has the Faraday pointer.
之前盯的那麼緊
He was such a good frame.
- 瓦任莎的情況如何 無恙但很焦慮
- What is Vayentha's condition? - Intact but anxious.
那也正常
She should be.
這位委託人究竟都讓我們做了些什麼
What in god's name has this client gotten us into?
不不不 只是個 ... 比方
No, no, no. This is uh... rhetorical.
我們什麼時候準備好發佈委託人的視頻
When are we due to release the client's video?
視頻剛到這
It just arrived.
他的指示是24小時內上傳
His instructions were to upload it in 24 hours.
我現在想看一下
I want to look at it now.
但 委託人 佐布裡斯特
But, the client, Mr. Zobrist.
委託人 委託人已經死了 我要看視頻
The client, the client is dead. I want to see the video.
這是違約行為
That's a violation of our protocols.
我們不是政府 只是負責辦事
We're not the government. We get things done.
阿博加斯特先生
Mr. Arbogast.
能夠令我們在工作中得心應手的首要因素
Chief among the attributes that makes us so very good at our job
正是世人對我們存在的一無所知
is that as far as the world is concerned, we don't exist.
倘若這段視頻暗示或甚至提及到我們
If this video implicates or even mentions us in anyway,
我就會基於客戶權益考慮而中止其發佈
I want to stop it's release. For the benefit of all our clients.
你要求過在流程操作中要避免異常事況 就這些
You asked me to avoid abnormalities in procedure, that's all.
如果佐布裡斯特先生當初只是在假裝正常交易 怎麼辦
What about Mr. Zobrist has ever remotely resembled normal.
- 那我．．．也只是個比方
- Well, I... - Also rhetorical.
把視頻帶過來
Bring me the video.
馬基雅維利大道
佛羅倫薩 意大利
維奇奧宮的五百人大廳內
In the Vecchio's Hall of the Five Hundred
上午 8:36
有一副著名壁畫
there's a famous mural
喬治奧·瓦薩裡的"馬西阿諾之戰"
Giorgio Vasari's Battle of Marciano.
在壁畫頂部附近 有一段密文
Near the top of the mural is a coded message
這也是藝術界中最著名的未解之謎
which is one the art world's most famous puzzles.
密文是什麼
And what's the message?
Cerca trova.
尋找 就尋見
Seek and find.
在醫院裡 我一直念叨說我很抱歉
At the hospital, I kept saying I was sorry.
很抱歉 一遍又一遍
Very sorry, over and over.
好吧 也許那不是我的本意
Well, maybe that's not what I meant.
畫家的名字瓦薩裡我可能講的是"瓦薩裡"
The name of the artist, Vasari. I could have been saying Vasari.
很棒啊 感覺你清醒多了
That's good. You seem clearer.
- 是的 你的中間名叫什麼
- I am. - What's your middle name?
呃 我挺清醒的
Well, I am.
嗯哼
Mm-hm.
佐布裡斯特死了 但若病毒真的存在
Zobrist is dead but if his plague is real...
那這幅"地獄圖"就是他留給某人找到它的線索
Then this map is a trail he has left so someone can find it.
誰
Who?
嗯 跟他立場一致的人
Well, someone who believes the same as he does.
那就是你帶著它的原因
And that's why you have it.
但我印象中從未見過他
Well, I don't remember ever meeting Zobrist.
你不記得的事情可多了
There's a lot you don't remember.
也許他們 也許他們之前找到你
Maybe they- Maybe they came to you.
徵求過你的指引
Wanted your help with the path.
- 就因為我做過但丁的講座- 正是如此
- Because I lectured on Dante? - Exactly.
他們向你展示法拉第指示器試著說服你支持那些主張
They showed you this Faraday pointer, tried to convince you of their cause.
- 大屠殺- 你說過他挺令人信服的
- Mass murder? - You said you found him compelling.
那是指觀點
His argument!
口才
His rhetoric.
絕非這些計劃 佐布裡斯特心理上有問題
Not his plan! Zobrist is a psychopath.
好吧 或許他們耍了你
Well, maybe they tricked you.
其實給了 ... 你認識的人
Sent... someone you knew.
離午夜還差一分鐘
It's a minute to midnight.
- 那是對付咱們的嗎- 常理來看是的
- Is that for us? - Logic would suggest.
該死
Damn it!
這兒 快 跟上我
Here, come on. Follow me.
我們可以穿過花園到那兒
We could get there through the garden.
好的 舊宮在這邊
Okay, the- the Palazzo Vecchio is this way.
過去一小時內我們標記了她用信用卡購買的汽車
We just flagged the car charged to her credit card within the past hour.
安托萬 你跟警方交涉了麼
Antoine, did you talk to the police?
那邊有見過咱們的警察
There are people who have seen me.
請跟當地警方合作
Please cooperate with local police officially.
WHO將負責監督波波利花園的搜查工作
W.H.O. will take charge overseeing the search at the Boboli Gardens.
把搜查犬調過來
Call in the search dogs.
我在警局裡接到電話 前來支援你
I got called out from the police station to support you.
波波利花園
上午8:42
我需要更多幫手
I need more people.
報告電台 發現嫌犯
Radio in, suspects found.
該死的 四組 檢查北邊
Damn it! Delta, check the north perimeter.
這兒下去有扇灰色的小門
There's a small gray door down here.
直通瓦薩里長廊
It will take us into the Vasari corridor.
穿過維奇奧橋 就進到了宮裡
Right across the Ponte Vecchio, and into the Palazzo.
- 門在那看- 哦
- That's the door, see. - Yeah.
就現在
Now!
花園是不是被牆整個圍住的
Is the garden completely walled.
四面全封閉
On all sides.
唯一的出口要穿過北面的碧提宮
The only exits are through the Palazzo Pitti, on the north side,
或者通過東西兩側接待遊客的大門
and through the visitors gates on the east and west sides.
沒有別的出路了
No other way out?
如果瓦薩里長廊大門也算的話
I suppose if you count the Vasari gate.
不過那門很老 鮮有人知
But it's ancient, no one knows about that.
蘭登知道
Langdon does.
教授現在是個麻煩了 瓦任莎
The Professor has become a liability, Vayentha.
教務長已經發佈了誅殺令 除掉蘭登
The provost has issued a kill order. Eliminate Langdon.
如若失敗 你要負責 我說得夠清楚了嗎
Fail, and you will be held accountable. Am I making myself clear?
明白了 長官
Copy that, sir.
五百人大廳
舊宮
早上 9:13
那兒
There.
瓦薩裡的壁畫 馬西阿諾之戰
That's the Vasari fresco, The Battle of Marciano.
那兒 那兒 看 看 看 看
There. There. Look. Look, look, look.
好的 看那兩棟農舍 壁畫中間往上
Okay, see the 2 farmhouses, dead center up high,
往4點鐘方向下移一點
come down to it's 4 o'clock,
你就看到一小面綠色戰旗
and you'll see a small green flag.
- Ｃｅｒｃａｔｒｏｖａ- 對
- Cerca trova. - Yeah.
尋找 就尋見
Seek and find.
咱們看到了 找到了
We sought it and we found it.
那麼 現在做什麼
So, now what?
佐布裡斯特加到畫裡的話
The words Zobrist added to the painting.
唯有透過死亡之眼 才能瞥見真相
The truth can be glimpsed only through the eyes of death.
死亡之眼
Eyes of death.
誰的眼睛
Whose's eyes?
我是不是被注射了什麼東西
Was I given an injection?
什麼時候
When?
- 醫院裡面頸動脈注射- 沒有
- At the hospital, with a hypertenol? - No.
沒有 你是插管輸液治療 只有靜脈滴注
No, you were intubated. Anything you got came through the IV.
不在醫院裡
Not at the hospital.
我當時身著正裝 在車廂後座上
I was fully dress. I was in the back of some car...
大概是過去兩天裡的某個時候
at some point in the last 2 days.
有東西注入了我的血液裡
And something was injected into my bloodstream.
然後現在我開始外現臨床病狀
and now I'm showing signs of an illness
會不會是...
What if...?
會是什麼
What if what?
西恩娜 我會不會就是攜帶者
Sienna, what if I'm the carrier?
你看
Look.
如果你攜帶了 那我也會被感染
If you've got it then I've got it too.
還有我們接觸過的每個人同樣如此 都會死掉
And everyone we've come into contact with has it and will likely die.
但如果並非如此
But if you don't.
如果 如果他們注射的是藥劑或致幻劑 或者別的東西
If-If they gave you an anotic or a hallucinogen or anything else.
那麼我們仍有機會挽救這半個世界
Then we still have a chance to save half the world.
值得一試 不是麼
It's worth a try, isn't it?
教授
Professor.
啊 真是你 你怎麼這麼快就回來了
Ah, it is you. Why are you back so soon?
我不知道她是誰
I have no idea who this woman is.
你這身行頭我差點沒認出來 在逛街嗎
I almost didn't recognize you in that suit. You've been shopping?
教授 你的頭被撞了
Professor, you bumped your head.
是的 洗澡的時候 暴跌一跤
In the shower, yes. It's quite a tumble.
- 哎呀
- 嗯
- Ayes. - Yeah.
打擾一下 這位是西恩娜 我的侄女
I'm sorry. This is Sienna, my niece.
你人在意大利呢 教授 不必提這個
You're in Italy, Professor, you don't have to say 'niece'.
- 不是不是的
- 不是的他沒有
- No. No. - No, he's not.
你好 瑪塔·阿爾瓦雷茲 很高興見到你
Hello. Marta Alvarez. Pleasure to meet you.
伊格納奇奧也跟你一塊來了嗎
小主教座堂 伊格納奇奧-
Is Ignazio with you again?
- 伊格納奇奧
- 對
- Ignazio? - Yeah.
伊格納奇奧今早沒能成行
Ignazio couldn't make it this morning.
很抱歉打攪你一下 瑪塔 不過
I'm sorry to bother you, Marta. But...
我想你大概能想到我為什麼會在這裡又一次
I can imagine you know why I'm back. Again.
真的嗎
Really?
舊宮裡頭這麼多的珍寶
Of all the treasures in the Palazzo.
昨天晚上他跟小主教座堂在那上面待了將近一個鐘頭
He and il Duomino spent almost an hour with it up there last night.
真的 非同尋常
It's-It's so morbid.
哪裡哪裡 這很正常
No. No. It's cool.
好了 來吧 我來帶路
Alright, come on. I'm headed up that way.
他真是足智多謀的一個能人
He's an extremely resourceful man.
我也對你說過這話 布沙爾先生
I was told you were as well, Mr. Bouchard.
那麼 告訴我
So. Tell me.
你覺得他在幹嘛
What do you think he's doing?
你覺得你在幹嘛
What you think you doing?
我把指示器帶給你 現在它沒了
I brought you the pointer and now it's gone.
- 你弄丟了- 我們在街上跟丟了他
- You have a leak. - We losed him in the street.
在醫生的住處又重新發現了
Reacquired him at the doctor's apartment.
有大家支持 我還能掌控
I can handle with some ground.
- 我們不需要你幫忙- 如果他受傷了
- We don't need your help. - What if he's injured.
頭部受創
A head wound.
什麼意思 你認為他糊塗了
What? You think he's confused.
- 他不知道他在幹嘛嗎- 有可能
- He doesn't know what he's doing? - It's possible.
他晚上失蹤前進展到了哪裡
How far did he get the night before he disappeared?
五百人大廳
To the Hall of Five Hundred.
那我們就不追了
So let's stop chasing him,
提前守著他
anticipate him instead.
嘿 朋友 還請悠著點
Whoa, inspector. Not so fast, please.
我快燃起來了
I'm about to burst.
這麼浪漫的一天他卻帶你來欣賞死亡面具
Such a romantic date he takes you on. To see a death mask.
是的 在16世紀 它們相當普遍
Yeah, they were common practice in the 1500s.
實質上就是某個人面部的石膏模型
It's essentially just a plaster cast of someone's face,
在其死後不久套模澆注的
made a few moments after that person dies.
"透過死亡之眼"
"Through the eyes of death."
這幅面具的模型 是一位詩人
The person who was used for this mask, the poet,
叫但丁
Dante.
我想這是一個浪漫的故事
It is a romantic story I supposed.
但丁熱愛這座城市他在當時很顯赫又有影響力但
Dante loved Florence, he was prominent and powerful. But...
在政治權力更迭後 他被罷黜流放
The political winds changed and he was exiled.
人們威脅他 若膽敢回來 就火刑伺候
They threatened to burn him at the stake if he ever returned.
實際上有人認為對但丁的放逐是面具看著如此悲慟的原因
Actually, some people say Dante's exile is the reason his death mask looks so sad.
不 不對 那是因為比阿特麗斯的原因
比阿特麗斯- 神曲
- 中的人物
No. No. It was because of Beatrice.
但丁只從遠處見過她但她卻被其終生迷戀
Dante only knew her from afar but he was obsessed with her his entire life.
你的侄女很浪漫呢 教授
Your niece is a romantic, Professor.
人們認為但丁所撰的穿越地獄之行實際上是為了找到她
They say Dante wrote in fact about his journey out of hell to reach her.
但他沒能成功
But he never made it.
她已嫁給另主
She married someone else.
這事常常發生
That happens.
有嗎
Does it?
誰撇下了誰
Who left who?
有些東西 若你不加以照料就會難以為繼
Things fall apart if you don't look after them.
噢 館方要求參觀時你們只能站在立柱外
Oh. We ask that you stay behind the stanchions. Please.
謝謝
Thank you.
來得很巧 教授 我們剛剛開門
Good timing, Professor. We've only just opened.
瑪塔...
Marta...
在
Yes?
那兒 那是我們
There. That's us.
伊格納奇奧·布索尼 -小主教座堂
那是伊格納奇奧·布索尼
That's Ignazio Busoni.
我們相識多年
I've known him for years.
他是研究但丁的學者
He's the Dante scholar.
面具的主人堅持要求參觀者要站在立柱之外
The mask's owner insists on the stanchions to keep people back.
未經許可 工作人員也不能打開展櫃
He doesn't even permit staff to open the case without him present.
所以面具不是博物館所有
So the mask is not owned by the museum?
不是 有位私人收藏家從我們手裡買下了
No. A private collector bought it from us,
並允許我們做永久性展覽
and allows us to display it in perpetuity.
這是籌集經費的慣常做法
It's a common practice, to raise funds.
他是何許人也
Who is the collector?
貝特朗·佐布裡斯特 那位億萬富翁
Bertram Zobrist, the billionaire.
他的觀點很古怪但其自殺之事仍舊令人遺憾
His ideas were quite eccentric, but still it's such a shame what happened.
那就是我接電話的時候了
That's when I got the call.
喔
Oh.
教授 我 我不知道該作何感想
Professor, I... I don't know what to think!
我很震驚
I am appalled!
- 教授- 蘭登教授
- Professor. - Professor Langdon.
瞧 這事情肯定有個解釋
Look. There's an explanation for all this.
警察來了 警鈴響了
The police came and the alarm went off.
這些都是什麼人
Who are they?
他們都是特工人員
They're government agents.
你有客人了
You have an intruder.
我馬上回來
I'll be right back.
瑪塔 別讓他倆跑了
Marta, don't let them go.
你不能帶槍進這來
You can not bring a gun here.
教授
Professor.
教授 我非常尊敬您 但我不明白
Professor, I very much respect you but I do not understand.
- 請坐我會解釋- 你為什麼做這事
- Please sit down. I'm going to explain this. - Why you have done this?
- 那可不行- 瑪塔我不知道面具在哪兒
- This is not okay. - Marta, I do not know where the mask is.
但我會竭盡全力找到它 還給你們
But I will do everything I can to find it and return it to you.
教授 你在幹嘛 教授 求你 不要
Professor, what are you doing? Professor, please. No.
教授 回來 別這樣
Professor, come back. Don't do that.
教授 請不要
Professor, please don't.
- 嘿嘿- 教授
- Hey. Hey. - Professor.
- 你別跟著就好- 求你了別這樣
- Just don't follow us. - Please, don't do this.
教授
Professor!
咱們偷偷找條路子離開這兒
Let's just calmly find a way out of here.
你為什麼不告訴我伊格納奇奧的事情
Why didn't you tell me about Ignazio?
如果你知道我是個賊 你還會幫我嗎
Would you help me if you knew I was a thief?
你向我求助的時候撒了謊
You lied to me when you asked for my help.
對 嚴格說來 我有所保留
Well technically, I withheld.
如果我真的拿了那副面具...
If I really took that mask...
你的確拿了 我剛剛才看到
You did take the mask, I just saw you.
這不是你的問題 你不必跟著
This is not your problem. You don't have to stay.
我當然要陪著 人類正面臨生死存亡
Of course, I do. Human lives are at stake.
我只想知道我沒站錯隊
I just want to know that I'm on the right side.
你沒有
You are.
我發誓
I swear.
好的
Good.
現在咱們去找到要找的東西
Now let's find what we're looking for.
打給伊格納奇奧 問他面具藏哪兒了
Call this Ignazio, and ask him where he hid the mask.
伊格納奇奧失蹤了 不知藏身何處
Ignazio's disappeared. He had gone into hiding.
他說過
He said.
別人也在追著他 但他留了條線索
They were chasing him too but he left a clue.
一封郵件 "天堂 25"
An email, "Paradise Twenty-five".
指的是但丁"神曲"中的天堂篇第25詩章不過
That's a reference to Dante's Divine Comedy. "Canto XXV." But...
- 我現在需要那本書- 一本書
- I need a copy of the book. - A copy of the book.
真荒誕 我會用谷歌
That's quaint. I use Google.
他們正在關閉博物館 只開放主出口
They're closing down the museum, only the main exit is going to be open.
那我們就穿過亞美尼亞
Well, then we'll go through Armenia.
...從正門有序離開
...Go out to the front door in an orderly manner.
現已封鎖全部出口
All exit doors are now sealed.
這是唯一的進出通道
This is the only way in or out.
有沒有隱藏的出口 隧道 隱門之類的
What about hidden exits? Tunnels, concealed doorways?
這地方700年了 先生 這類玩意很多
It's a 700 year old Palazzo, Signore, there are a number of them.
帶我看看
Show me.
亞美尼亞
ARMENIA
教授 真是刮目相看
Professor. How worldly.
舊宮的秘密之一
Secrets of the Palazzo Invisibile.
這段路很贊 改天你也試試
It's a great tour, you should take it sometime.
我們在這兒暫時安全了
We should be safe here for a minute.
進去
Go.
"到那時我將帶著另一個聲音另一身羊毛..."
"By then with other voice, with other fleece..."
"我將作為詩人回歸並且在我的洗禮盆中接受那花冠..."
"I shall return as poet and put on,at my baptismal font, the laurel crown..."
洗禮盆
Baptismal font.
聖母百花大教堂 但丁受洗之地
Il Duomo--佛羅倫薩主教座堂 廣場建築群 包括聖母百花大 教堂 聖若望洗禮堂 喬托鐘樓等
Il Duomo. The Cathedral where Dante was baptized.
也是伊格納奇奧工作的地方他把面具藏在那了
That's where Ignazio works. That's where he hid the mask.
不在這兒
It is not here.
他們會認為我們正前往出口
They're going to think we're heading down to the exit.
那麼我們往上走
Then we go up.
好的
Alright.
我們正在五百人大廳上面
We're right above the Hall of Five Hundred.
另一頭有道樓梯 直通大街
There's a stairway leading down to the street on the other side.
那麼
So.
一次邁一步
One step at a time.
行嗎
Okay?
你恐高不
Are you afraid of heights?
有點兒
A little.
我倒是有點兒幽閉恐懼症
I'm uncomfortable in tight spaces.
那麼 別往下看
So, don't look down.
或者就往下看 我記不得了
Or do. I can never remember which.
沒那麼難
It's not that hard.
來吧 走
Come on, go.
西恩娜
Sienna!
你還好嗎
Are you alright?
- 你還好嗎
- 還好
- You okay? - Yeah.
好的 只要... 慢慢去到那邊橫樑上
Alright, just... crawl along that beam there.
我在另一邊跟你碰頭 樓梯附近
And I'll meet you on the far side, by the ladder.
長官
Sir.
調派六個人到這來 不用戒備了
Give me a six men stationed here. Safeties off.
你現在變蠢了 蘭登教授
You're being stupid now, Professor Langdon!
走 走 離開這兒 走
Go. Go. Get out of here, go!
他們一度需要你 但如今心意已改
They needed you but now they changed their minds.
把人都趕走 大家都離開 清空現場
Get these people out. Everyone out, clear the room.
把它給我
Give me that.
那些門 這兒
These doors, here.
- 東面他們去那了- 收到
- Eastern side. That's where they're headed. - Okay.
走 行動 快點
Go, move. Quickly!
布沙爾 布沙爾探員 回話
Bouchard. Agent Bouchard, come in.
你在哪兒 布沙爾探員 回話
What is your location? Agent Bouchard, come in.
重生
REBIRTH
寄來視頻的信封上也有這個詞
That same word is on the envelope the video arrived in,
重生
上面還有一個日期 是明天
along with the date. The date is tomorrow.
謝謝 這些我知道
Well, thank you, that was not lost on me.
地獄中最黑暗的地方 是為那些
The darkest places in hell are reserved for those
在道德危機時刻皂白不辨的人而準備的
who refuse to act in time of moral crisis.
但丁的地獄並非虛構 它是預言
Dante's hell isn't fiction anymore, it's prophecy.
我們已經在這個星球上打造了人間地獄
We have created our own hell on earth.
天吶
Oh my.
警告已然很明顯 對策卻被忽略了
The warnings have been obvious, the solutions ignored.
因此 我採取了行動
So, I took action.
如果你看到了這則視頻就意味著地獄病毒
If you are watching this, it means the Inferno virus was released
已在昨晚午夜被釋放
last night at midnight, and...
現在早就傳遍了全球各個角落
it's now being carried to every corner of the Earth.
天吶
Oh my.
在釋放後的6天內 病毒會不斷增殖
上帝用6天創造天地
Within 6 days of it's released, the virus will replicate itself.
地球上的全體人類數量
And every man, woman and child on Earth expect the current...
將會隨機減半
the current population to be culled by half.
倖存者則將見證
The survivors will witness
這個星球上前所未有的恐怖
horrors... unknown to this planet.
但我想讓大家知道原由
But I want them to know why.
這就是吾之所為 這就是吾之救贖
That this was our doing and this is our salvation.
現在時候已到
Now is the time.
今天是...
Today is...
後面還有
There's more.
我相信我已經明白了視頻主旨
I believe I've got the gist.
很明顯過去數年以來
It appears our organization has spent
我們在跟一個試圖通過自行研發的致命病毒
the last several years in the employ of a madman
來發動人口大屠殺的瘋子在打交道
who now intends to commit a mass murder using a deadly plague of his own creation
在接下來24小時的某一刻 ... 抱歉
in some point in the next 24... Sorry.
不到12小時了
Less than 12 hours.
那麼 咱們盡吾所能 不要再
So, let's do our level best not to fuck things up
把事兒進一步搞砸了 好嗎
any worse than we already have, shall we?
沒了法拉第指示器 沒人能找到病毒
Without the Faraday pointer, no one can find the virus.
蘭登教授現在在哪
Where is Professor Langdon now?
他之前跟布魯克斯醫生在波波利花園但情報似乎斷了
He was with Dr. Brooks in the Boboli Gardens but we seemed to have lost visual.
我們恐怕也有很久沒有聯繫上瓦任莎了
And I'm afraid we have no contact from Vayentha.
知道了
I see.
我親自去佛羅倫薩
I'm going to Florence myself.
給她做傳染性檢查 把這裡隔離起來
Test her for signs of contagion and quarantine this place.
如果不盡快找到蘭登
If we don't find Langdon very soon,
我們很快就會看到更多死屍
we are going to be looking at a great many more dead bodies.
你還好嗎
Are you alright?
虛弱
It's weakness.
只是虛弱 該死的
Just weakness, god damn it.
我們歇一會兒
We'll just take a moment.
你見到她掉下去了嗎
Did you see her down there?
是的
Yes.
自打我11歲開始 全部所做所學
Everything I've done, every bit of work and studies since I was eleven
就是去救死扶傷 而不是置人死地
is to stop death, not cause it.
那只是自衛 有人要刺殺咱們
It was self defense. Someone was trying to kill us.
我不知道能不能跟下去了
I don't know if I can finish this.
你不能的話 我完全理解
I understand if you can't.
看 佐布裡斯特才是謀殺犯 不是你
Look, Zobrist is the murderer, not you.
你救了我
You saved me.
你本不必採取行動的
You don't have to take another step.
嗯 說的沒錯
Yeah, you're right.
我做了應該做的若有必要我還會再來一遍
I did what was necessary and I'll do it again if I need to.
我祈願這是最後一次
I pray that you don't.
看樣子已經關門在搞維修了
Looks like it's close for repairs.
好的 這邊
Okay, this way.
聖若望洗禮堂
那兒
There.
洗禮盆
The baptismal font.
又是但丁
Dante again.
總是但丁 為什麼是但丁
Always Dante, why Dante?
- 丙烯底塗料- 你指顏料嗎
- Acrylic gesso. - You mean paint.
水性顏料
Water soluble paint.
聞著像是落水狗
Smells like a wet dog.
看那 有筆跡
Look at that. There's a writing.
"尋找那位欺詐的威尼斯總督
"Seek the treacherous Doge of Venice,
- 他曾切斷馬匹之頭〞- 威尼斯
- who severed the heads from horses." - Venice.
但丁在那兒身染虐疾 最終客死異鄉
Where Dante was infected with the disease that killed him.
"跪在金碧輝煌的神聖智慧博學園內
"Kneel within the gilded museum of holy wisdom,
聆聽小溪的流水之聲"
and listen for the sounds of trickling water."
"下到水下宮殿深處
"Follow deep into the sunken palace,
- 冥府怪物就在此間等待- 說的是病毒
- where the chthonic monster waits." - The plague itself.
水面以下
Underwater.
"淹沒在血紅的水下
"Submerged in the blood-red waters of
- 那裡的瀉湖不會倒映群星- 教授
- of the lagoon that reflects no stars." - Professor.
請問你能告訴我你到底在搞什麼鬼嗎
Could you please tell me what the hell you are doing?
為什麼你還不來幫忙
Why haven't you called in?
你是誰
Who are you?
克裡斯托夫·布沙爾 世界衛生組織
Christoph Bouchard, from the World Health Organization.
- 我們見過的
- 我們見過
- We've met. - We've met?
你真的不記得了麼 才過了兩天
You really don't remember? It was just 2 days ago.
他頭部受傷 這是副作用
He's suffering the effects of a head wound.
無法記起過去兩天發生的事情
He can't remember the events for the last 48 hours.
我就是飛到劍橋向你尋求幫助的那位
哈佛大學位於美國劍橋市
I'm the one who flew to Cambridge and asked for your help.
我給了你指示器 你負責解密
I gave you the pointer to decode.
蘭登先生
Mr. Langdon.
我是
Yes.
好吧 我想起來了
Okay. I remember.
你是誰
Who are you?
我是教授在醫院裡救助時急診室的醫生
I was the ER doctor at the hospital when the Professor came in.
你最後能記起來的事情是什麼
What is the last thing you remember?
我在大街上 我覺得就在這裡
I was on the street. I think it was here.
還陪著位女士
I was with a woman.
-然後被注射了東西-伊麗莎白·辛斯基
- And I was given an injection. - Elizabeth Sinskey.
伊麗莎白
Elizabeth?
也是世衛組織的
From the World Health Organization.
你認識她麼
Do you know her?
是的
I do.
但我好幾年沒見過她了
But I haven't seen Elizabeth in years.
她就是我單獨跟著你們的原因
She's the reason I followed you alone.
你的意思是
What do you mean?
我相信辛斯基博士正與外國政府協作
I believe Dr. Sinskey is working with a foreign government
在合力尋找並外銷病毒
to find and sell the virus.
不不不 那不可能
No. No. No. That's not possible.
人是會變的 教授
People change, Professor.
我已經追捕貝特朗·佐布裡斯特兩年了
I've been chasing Bertrand Zobrist for 2 years.
一直有人在竭力反對我
And someone has been working against me.
咱們講重點 你知道病毒在哪裡嗎
Let's get to the point. You know where the virus is?
我猜你應該有身份證明吧
I assume you have some sort of credentials.
要問WHO的話你請便
Call WHO if you like.
查一下我 但動作快點
Check me out, but do it quickly.
威尼斯 我覺得在威尼斯
Venice. We think it's Venice.
很好
Good.
坐火車要兩小時 跟我來吧
It's 2 hours by train. Come on.
如果我能找到你 別人也可以
If I could find you, so can the others.
我給你們都買張去日內瓦的機票
I'm buying you both plane tickets to Geneva.
不 不是日內瓦 他說是威尼斯
No, not Geneva. He said Venice.
我聽到了
I heard that.
讓一下 請大家注意
Excuse us. Please watch yourselves.
請退後 讓一下
Step back, please. Excuse us.
讓一下
Excuse us.
請大家注意
Watch yourself, please.
-這是飛日內瓦的班機嗎-是的不過登機口剛剛關閉了
- This is the plane to Geneva? - Yes, but we just closed the door.
讓飛機待那別動 我們要檢查全部乘客
Keep the plane at the gate. We need to check every passenger.
那就是在浪費時間了
That would be a waste of time.
而且我們的時間很緊
And we have very little of that.
9982次 意大利-威尼斯
下午 1:57
三天前在歷經兩年的追查後我們找到了佐布裡斯特
3 days ago, after 2 years of searching, I found Zobrist.
他然後自殺了但我們在他口袋裡找到一個包裹
He killed himself. But we took a package from his pocket.
裡面是什麼
And what was in it?
裝有"地獄圖"的法拉第指示器
The Faraday pointer with the map of hell.
是一個謎題 專門為其擁護者解謎而設計的
A puzzle, specifically designed for his followers to solve.
我們把它交給了你
We brought it to you.
你正在解密的時候
And you were in the process of decoding it,
被人給綁架了
when you were kidnapped.
蘭登教授
Professor Langdon.
-你當時跟辛斯基博士在一塊-伊麗莎白對的
- You were with Dr. Sinskey at the time. - Elizabeth, yes.
她有沒有向你透露任何對病毒感興趣的第三方組織
Did she tell you about any third party interest in the virus?
-不記得了- 她在經濟上是不是有困難
- I don't remember. - Did she have financial problems?
呃 我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
她有沒有帶著備用手機
Did she carry more than one cellphone?
不知道
I don't know.
- 想一下
- 他不記得了
- Think. - He doesn't remember.
那就告訴我誰能記得教授"不知道不記得"真是夠了
Then tell me who can remember, Professor! Enough with the "I don't know, I don't remember."!
這樣對他不好
It's not good for him.
那個"金碧輝煌的博學園"是在威尼斯聖馬可大教堂內
The "gilded museum" is that Saint Mark's.
整個威尼斯都是博學園
All of Venice is a museum.
那兒有"聖馬爾谷之馬"雕塑 它們都是銅像
St. Mark's has the Horses of Constantinople, they're bronze statues.
我可以看看嗎
Can I see that?
是我我就不會碰它
I wouldn't touch it.
我也不打算那樣
I wasn't planning on it.
教授
Professor.
蘭登教授
Professor Langdon.
是我
Yes.
你好 羅伯特
Hello, Robert.
伊麗莎白
Elizabeth.
好久不見
It's been a long time.
太久了
Too long.
是什麼風把你吹來了
What brings you here?
WHO需要你的幫助
The WHO needs your help.
我的幫助
My help?
我希望你還記得但丁
I hope you still remember your Dante.
剛剛發生了什麼
What just happened?
你還好嗎
Are you alright?
你能弄點水嗎 他可能脫水了
Could you get some water? He could be dehydrated.
弄點吃的或者水果 或者列車上別的什麼
Some food, maybe some fruit or something from the machine.
- 快點- 好的
- Quickly. - Sure.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 他在撒謊嗎- 他在撒謊
- Is he lying? - Through his teeth.
他不是那天來找我的人
He was not the one who came to Cambridge to see me.
布沙爾 快來幫我 快點 我覺得他虛脫了
Bouchard, I need help, quickly. I think he's collapsed.
這門我打不開
I can't open the door.
蘭登
Langdon?
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
蘭登 你還好嗎
Langdon, are you okay?
快點 咱們走
Come on, let's go!
中央火車站
帕多瓦
你在告訴我過去兩年來
You're telling me that for 2 years,
你和你的組織都在跟我作對嗎
you and your organization have been working against me.
沒錯
That is correct.
掩飾貝特朗·佐布裡斯特和他的研究
To shield Bertrand Zobrist and his research.
- 藏著他保護他- 很遺憾是的
- To hide him, to protect him. - Regrettably, yes.
而我全部的避免他引發全球性流行病的嘗試
And that all of my attempts to prevent him from initiating
都因為你們在從中作梗而失敗了
a worldwide pandemic have failed because of you.
簡單概括的話 是的
An incisive sum-up, yes.
現在你又冒冒失失的跑來 要求我相信你
Now you have the temerity to ask that I simply decide to trust you?
非常抱歉 在我看來 別無他法
I'm terribly sorry, I didn't see any other way.
你的團隊 到底是幹什麼的
Who exactly does your group work for?
當然是服務於客戶
Our clients, of course.
我們是一家私人安保公司 運作得很成功
We are a private security firm. A very successful one.
我可以請問一下
May I ask,
之前與你共事的那位紳士 布沙爾探員
the gentleman who was with you, agent Bouchard,
他現在在哪兒
where is he now?
我們不得而知 他已經失去行蹤了
We don't know. We lost track of him.
那麼現在的情況要比你們想像的還糟
Then the situation is worse than you think.
只有唯一一種原因會令他選擇失聯
There is only one reason he would move out of contact,
他想要獨自找到蘭登先生
he wants Mr. Langdon to himself.
為什麼
Why?
找到病毒 然後再抬價轉手 我猜的
To find the virus and sell it to the highest bidder I assume.
借貸收購 敲詐勒索 你懂的 老一套
Leverage, blackmail, you know, the usual shit.
我覺得咱們不必再深入討論了西姆斯先生
I don't think we have anything further to discuss, Mr. Sims.
尋找病原體的時間已經不足8小時 抱歉
And I have less than 8 hours to find this pathogen, excuse me.
據我所知 在此之前你就認識教授
From what I understand, you knew the Professor sometime ago.
有過私交
Personally.
你在乎他
You care about him.
你甚至會為了保護他而跟像我這種不擇手段的人合作不是嗎
You would even ally with
an unscrupulous character
such as myself to protect
him, wouldn't you?
我的組織就有找到蘭登教授的資源
My organization has the resources to find your Professor.
威尼斯 意大利
下 午  2: 49
若你想要散播瘟疫 這兒就是理想之地
If you wanted to start a plague, this is where you do it.
沒錯
Yep.
這兒每年有兩千萬遊客來自全球各地的遊客
20 million people a year come here from every corner of the globe.
14世紀黑死病肆虐期間威尼斯人號令全部船隻
During the Black Death, the
Venetians made all the ships
在港口拋錨停泊40天
anchored in the harbor for 40 days,
隨後才允許船員入城
before they would allow the crews into the city.
以確保瘟疫不會傳入城內
Making sure that they were not carrying the Plague.
英文中"隔離"一詞就是來自意大利語
The word "Quarantine" comes from the Italian.
還有"四十" 來自"Quaranta"
"quaranta", "forty".
有你陪同感覺很棒呢 教授
It's nice to have you back, Professor.
那兒 馬雕在那兒
There, the horses.
馬雕-聖馬爾谷之馬
都是複製品 原件在聖殿內部保管 (原因: 空氣污染)
These were recreations, the originals are in a museum for preservation.
得趕緊了 布沙爾知道我們會到這兒
We should be quick. Bouchard knows we are coming here.
打擾一下
Excuse me.
問一下那位導遊這些雕塑的馬頭有沒有被切下過
Ask that guide, if the heads have ever been severed from these horses?
打擾一下 打擾一下
Excuse me. Excuse me.
- 打擾一下- 麻煩了打擾一下
- Excuse me. - Please excuse me.
麻煩了
Please.
傳說在第四次十字軍東征期間(1202年-1204年)
According to the tale, during the Crusades,
拜占庭的君士坦丁堡-
今伊斯坦布爾
這些馬雕被威尼斯軍隊從拜占庭的君士坦丁堡劫走
the horses were looted from Constantinople.
馬匹...
Horses...
但它們實在太大 難以裝船
But they were too large to be loaded on board the ships,
所以馬頭被切下 隨後再重新接回
so their heads were removed and reattached.
哪位總督干的
By whom?
那位長生不老的總督 恩裡科·丹多洛
第任四十一威尼斯總督 恩裡科·丹多洛-
The doge who lived forever, Enrico Dandolo.
- 恩裡科·丹多洛- 長生不老的總督
- Enrico Dandolo. - The doge who lived forever.
當然了 恩裡科·丹多洛
Of course, Enrico Dandolo.
丹多洛把威尼斯人騙入十字軍中
Dandolo tricked the Venetians into the Crusades.
他原本應當率眾前往埃及卻跑去把君士坦丁堡給洗劫了
He was supposed to sail his ships to Egypt, but he sacked Constantinople instead.
我很抱歉 當然是他了
I'm sorry. Of course.
"金碧輝煌的神聖智慧博學園"
"The gilded museum of holy wisdom."
我們找錯了教堂嗎
Are we in the wrong basilica?
我們找錯了國家
We're in the wrong country.
丹多洛逝世後 並沒有埋葬在此
Dandolo passed, but he was not buried here.
那他葬在哪裡
So where was he buried?
聖索菲亞大教堂
Hagia Sophia.
- 伊斯坦布爾
伊斯坦布爾 -土耳其
- Istanbul. - Istanbul.
總會有出路的
There's always a way out.
在這兒 這兒
Here. Here.
看看你能不能把那個打開來
See if you could get that open.
我抓住你的腳了
I got your foot.
能搞定嗎
Can you get it?
外頭有人嗎
Is there someone there?
請幫一下
Please help.
對 對
Yes.
拉我一把
Give me a hand.
- １００塊
- 好的好的
- One hundred. - Yes! Yes.
- １００歐元
- 給我有我有的
- A hundred euro. - Here. I got it. I got it.
快 快 快
Quick. Quick. Quick.
謝謝
Thank you.
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?
你說過他是個謀殺犯 是個精神變態
You called him a murderer, a psychopath.
什麼
What?
但歷史會把我們視為救世主
But history will call us saviors.
天吶 我的天吶
Oh my god. Oh my god.
我不怕死 羅伯特
I'm not afraid to die, Robert.
但無所事事才是令我害怕的
But doing nothing terrifies me.
指引 指示器他是要留給你的佐布裡斯特
The path, and the pointer, he left that all for you, Zobrist.
- 你認識他嗎
- 何止認識
- You knew him? - Knew him?
我愛他
I loved him.
你這套衣服就是他的
You're wearing his suit.
不 西恩娜 不
No. Sienna, no.
謝謝你 羅伯特
Thank you, Robert.
謝謝你做的一切
Thank you for everything.
不 不 西恩娜 不要
No. No. Sienna, no.
西恩娜
Sienna!
不 西恩娜 西恩娜 不要
No, Sienna! Sienna, no!
慢點 慢點 你太快啦
Slow down, slow down. You're too fast.
噢 拜託 拜託
Oh, come on. Come on.
這個費了我三天時間
This took me 3 days.
太簡單啦
Too easy.
馬克·吐溫
鍍金時代
我很喜歡
I love it.
認識你之前
Everything before you exist,
完美生活還是臆想
an idea.
如今已經成真了
And now it's real.
愛 讓 靈魂 復甦
Love awaken the soul to act.
這可不公平 拿但丁來比喻我
That's not fair. Quoting Dante to me.
不過詩句裡是"美" 而不是"愛"
But it's beauty, not love.
怎麼了
What?
離午夜還差一分鐘
It's a minute to midnight.
比我預想的還要早
Sooner than I expected.
我們要去哪
Where're we going?
噢
Oh.
我明白了
I see.
我們一同策劃 一同構思
We planned it together, we designed it together,
但這部分只有你才知曉
but this part only belongs to you.
你不知道在哪 才會更安全
It's just safer if you don't know where.
如果他們搶先找到了你呢
What if they find you first?
那時怎麼辦
What then?
如果你想知道 你也不是一個人
If you want to know, you're not alone.
你得開始相信我
You got to start by trusting me.
我們若不立即採取大膽行動
Unless we take bold immediate action
第六次大滅絕就會輪到我們頭上
the sixth extinction will be our own.
你說得對
You were right.
我要給你安排另一條路
I'm going to make you another path.
地獄也在盡頭
Inferno will be at the end.
如果我遇到不測 第一條線索就會發給你
If something should happen to me, the first clue will be deliver to you.
我知道你會做好必須要做的事情
I know you'll do what must to be done.
尋找 就尋見
Seek and find.
你不是一個人
You're not alone.
那麼
So.
漂亮的小妮子跑去找壞傢伙了
The beautiful young woman went for the bad guy.
這事常常發生
That happens.
你看著好失望呢
You look disappointed.
我先讓你緩一緩
I'll give you a minute.
伊麗莎白並非是想要轉賣病毒的人
Elizabeth is not the one who wants the virus to sell.
那人是你
You are.
你被人利用了
You've been used.
有人在精心計劃 驅使你為他們效力
Elaborate schemes created by people to get you to do what they want.
至於我
But me,
我就簡單粗暴了
I'm very direct.
現在我正掌握一個絕佳的機會
And this is a moment of great opportunity for me.
所以 病毒在哪裡
So, where is the virus?
拜託 教授
Come on, Professor.
人世間生命幾何
How much life is there in the world?
有多少生來就在困苦掙扎
How much more is fighting to be born?
偶爾自相殘殺也並無過錯
Nothing wrong with thinning the herd once in a while.
很正常
It's healthy.
我已見過許多天意
I've seen many acts of god.
我是說 颱風 霍亂 你知道嗎
I mean, typhoons, cholera. And you know what?
有時候帶走的 還是善人之命
Sometimes it hits the right people.
- 慘無人性- 人之常情本就是不人道的
- That's inhuman. - Humanity is inhuman.
人命或許輕賤 但從未有人停止過
Life maybe cheap, but the means to end it on a mass scale,
探求滅絕眾生的方法手段
no one ever stops paying for that.
我再最後問你一...
I'm going to ask you for the last...
萬分抱歉
Terribly sorry.
沒別的法子了
Didn't see any other way.
須得迅雷不及掩耳 見血越少 效果越好
Must do this quickly. The less blood the better.
你是哪位
Who are you?
噢 一名協作者
Oh, a facilitator.
除了別的業務 我們公司還製造幻覺
Among other things my company creates illusions.
你的頭部並沒有受傷
You never had a real head wound.
- 但我失憶了
- 是化學作用
- But I lost my memory. - Chemically induced.
我們給你注射的是苯二氮□類藥物 (精神藥物)
We gave you an injection of benzodiazapenes.
抱歉 會伴有皮疹 一兩天後就消退
Sorry, it can produce a skin rash. It should fade in a day or so.
這些都是...
All this was a...
這些都是假的嗎
All this was a fake?
我更喜歡製造真實感
I prefer created reality.
我的手下綁架了你
My agents kidnapped you.
為了觸發全新的劇情他們消去了你的記憶
They cleared your memories so we could create a fresh scenario,
由此你便投身於協助我們的思路中
whereby you would be invested in the idea of helping us.
我們在你頭皮上劃了一道小口子這是槍擊幻覺的一部分
A small incision was made in your scalp to give the impression of a bullet graze.
醫院裡的門也是假鎖的
There are no locks on hospital doors.
沒錯
Exactly.
滿分回答
Highest marks.
醫院裡殺人的那位女警察呢
What about the policewoman who shot the Doctor in the hospital?
也是我的人
Also it's me.
她的槍裡是空包彈
Her gun fired blanks.
門上則有爆炸偽造的槍擊效果
And there were squibs in the door.
醫生是演員 身上掛著袋血漿包
The doctor was an agent wearing a blood packet.
出租車司機 整個醫院都是咱們的人
The taxi driver, the hospital was working for us as well.
在舊宮裡她試圖要殺了我
At the Palazzo Vecchio she tried to kill me.
那是真槍實彈
It was real bullets.
我要求的
At my behest.
當事情快要敗露時
When things that appeared to go tits up
我會試圖趕緊殺人滅口 毀屍滅跡
I try to sweep it all away quickly.
所以要殺我
By killing me?
我深表歉意 蘭登先生
I apologize unreservedly, Mr. Langdon.
我的確失去了一名老部下
I did lose an experienced agent.
這個行當裡 我見過的情況夠多了
There's a great deal of situation I've been informed in my line of work.
瞧 我知道的就這些
Look, hear me what I know.
我知道我看著很滲人
I know I've behaved terribly.
但謎題需要破解 這一點你最棒了
But a puzzle needed solving, who better to solve it than you.
瞟一眼 好嗎
Glance at it, will you?
幹得差強人意了
Not my best work.
但足以應付意大利人
But it will do for the Italians.
西恩娜來找我求助的時候佐布裡斯特早已擁躉者眾
Zobrist had followers everywhere when Sienna first came to me for help.
至少我是這麼認為的
Or so I thought.
佐布裡斯特死後不久 她就很嚴肅地找上門來
She came to us with serious concerns shortly after Zobrist died.
不知怎的 她知道了我們受雇於佐布裡斯特
Somehow, she knew Zobrist had hired us.
她表示這位富翁的生物研究成果 可能已經落到壞人手中
She said he was doing biological work that could be fallen into the wrong hands.
她並未提及瘟疫 但我們已經開始警惕
She didn't mention a plague. But we heard enough to be alarmed.
於是我們同意協助她 找到佐布裡斯特的計劃
So we agreed to work with her to find Zobrist's project.
然後當辛斯基博士帶你來時 我們看到了機會
And when Dr. Sinskey brought you in, we saw an opportunity.
當時是伊麗莎白來找我的
It was Elizabeth who came to see me.
是的
Yes.
從布沙爾探員手上 辛斯基博士弄到了法拉第指示器
Dr. Sinskey got the Faraday pointer from agent Bouchard.
她帶去讓你解密
She brought it to you to decode,
甚至用你的指紋來設作密碼
and she even secured it with your thumbprint.
我們別無選擇
That left us with no choice,
所以我們在街上把你搶了過來
so we took you from her on the street.
醫院裡的情況促使你相信布魯克斯醫生
The hospital scenario encouraged you to trust Dr. Brooks.
你們給領事館打電話時 另一頭接通的是我們
When you called to the Consulate it was answered by our man.
蘭登教授
Professor Langdon?
謝天謝地你還活著 我們一直在找你
Thank heavens you're alive. We've been looking for you.
東西你還帶著嗎
Are you still in possession?
你帶著指示器 我們跟著你
You had the pointer and we had you.
一切都推進的天衣無縫 直到布魯克斯女士把你引開
It was all working seamlessly until Miss. Brooks stole you away.
以確保病毒得以釋放
To make sure the virus is released.
看來
It appears.
年輕人很失望
Young people are disappointing.
我發現他們35歲左右時 就挺有耐性的了
I find them become tolerable around 35.
你提到過辛斯基博士
You mentioed Dr. Sinskey.
我一直很擔心你
I've been so worried.
你還好嗎
Are you alright?
- 我很好
- 是嗎
- I'm fine. - Are you?
我很好
I'm okay.
挺好的
I'm alright.
謝天謝地
Thank god.
- 你知道病毒在哪兒嗎
- 伊斯坦布爾
- Do you know where the virus is? - Istanbul.
世界衛生組織專機
下午 5:32
現在正是時候
Now's the time.
今天是重生之日
Today is rebirth.
地獄就是救贖
Inferno is salvation.
我很抱歉把你捲進來 羅伯特
I am so sorry I brought you into this, Robert,
- 在這麼多年之後
- 沒事我很高興你那麼做了
- after all these years. - No. I'm glad you did.
我見過他 佐布裡斯特 兩年前
I met him, you know. Zobrist, 2 years ago.
他當時向我求助
He asked for my help.
他想讓WHO支持他的行動
He wanted the WHO to endorse mass sterilization
對飲用水和主食中進行大規模殺菌消毒
in drinking waters and staple foods.
於是我下了逐客令 把他列為監控對像
So I threw him out of my office, put him on the watch list.
但他失蹤了...
But he disappeared and...
我猜那就是他僱傭了西姆斯的時候
I suppose that's when Zobrist hired Sims.
我早應該發... 我不知道
I should probably have... have I don't know.
怎麼
What?
這些都不是你的錯 你總要為它們責怪自己
You always blame yourself for things that weren't your fault.
嘴還是很甜
Still very sweet.
這邊 有個門口
Here, a doorway.
我希望見面那會 是別的事情呢
I wish it would have happened differently, back then.
咱們當時沒有經營好 就這麼散了
We didn't look after it. It fell apart.
這算是後悔嗎
Is that a regret?
我想起來的時候才會這樣
Only when I think about it.
你知道嗎 在門口那發生的最有意思的事情是
You know, the most interesting things happened in doorways,
那樣一種持續的臨界狀態
at the borders, right along the edges.
古代漁民會在寒暖洋流交匯處打漁
Ancient fishermen learned to sail where the warm water met the cold.
小魚會滯留在暖流邊上
The little fish would reach the edge of the warm water and they stopped.
然後大魚就從寒流裡游過來 把它們吃掉
And the big fish would come out of the cold water and they eat them.
最後是漁民們
And the fishermen.
嗯 漁翁得利
Well, they caught everybody.
門口那兒
Doorways.
你還是老樣子 羅伯特
Not one part of you has changed, Robert.
話癆一個
You talk too much.
嗯 一點也沒變
And then, not at all
伊麗莎白
Elizabeth.
我無法請求你別去日內瓦
I couldn't ask you not to go to Geneva.
做不到
I couldn't.
我也不想讓你離開劍橋市
I didn't want to ask you to leave Cambridge.
事情就是這麼發生的嗎
Was that how it happened?
我不能再相信記憶了
I don't trust my memory anymore.
我從未忘記任何事情
I never forget anything.
好吧 那是天賦
Well, that's a gift.
不 不是的
No, it isn't.
離他遠點 嘿 嘿 你們在幹嘛
Leave him alone! Hey! Hey! What are you doing?
離他遠點
Leave him alone!
轉過身去
Turn around!
別看我 賤貨 轉過頭去
Don't look at me, bitch, look away!
住手
Stop it!
別看
Don't look!
羅伯特
Robert!
伊斯坦布爾 土耳其
傍晚 6:39
謝謝你
Thank you.
伊斯坦布爾大學
我是詩人的朋友
I'm a friend of the poet.
佐布裡斯特為之捨身的是
For what did Zobrist die?
保全他人得生
That others may live.
我千里迢迢趕來 是要保證一切順利進行
I've come very far to make sure nothing interferes.
我們設計好的傳送系統 會在今晚午夜釋放病毒藥劑
The delivery system we designed will discharge the viral agent by midnight tonight.
但是有人正趕來要阻止這一切
But there are others who are on their way to stop it.
我得搶先找到它
I need to find it before they do
引爆炸彈 確保病毒被釋放
and trigger an explosion to ensure it's released.
我們如何幫忙
How do we help?
在查士丁尼大瘟疫期間
During the Plague of Justinian,
伊斯坦布爾每天有5000人死於街頭
5000 people died everyday in the streets in Istanbul.
東西方交流的又一個門戶
A border between East and West, another doorway.
這是他選中此地的原因
Which is why he chose it.
如果袋子沒有破損 我們可以裝住它
If the bag is intact, we can contain it.
但若有人先發制人 把它弄破了
But if someone ruptures it before we get there
47天內 95%的地球人口會受感染
95% of the earth's population will be infected in 47 days.
聖索菲亞大教堂
傍 晚  7: 53
教授 博士
Professor. Doctor.
我是米爾沙特 這兒的負責人
My name is Mirsat, I'm the curator here.
你有沒有徹底疏散建築內的人群
Have you completely evacuated the building?
我們竭盡全力了 但這地方實在太大
Well, to the extent that we can but the place is massive.
你可以告訴我要找的東西具體是什麼嗎
Could you tell me specifically what it is you're looking for?
恩裡科·丹多洛之墓
The tomb of Enrico Dandolo.
好的 這邊請
Of course, this way.
丹多洛
恩裡科
"跪在金碧輝煌的神聖智慧博學園內
"Kneel within the gilded museum of holy wisdom,
聆聽小溪的流水聲"
and listen for the sounds of trickling water."
"下到水下宮殿深處"
"Follow deep into the sunken palace."
我聽到地面下有流水聲
I hear water flowing under these stones.
它流向哪兒
Where does it go?
只是個排水道 流入到市政蓄水池裡
It's just drainage. It goes to the city cistern.
我們要找的是一個大型地下空間
We're looking for a large, underground space,
內部可能有支柱和人工照明
perhaps with columns, artificially lit from within.
那簡單 古人的供水系統
That's simple. The ancient system,
16世紀 沉沒的宮殿
sixth century, Yerebatan Sarayi.
也被稱為"地下水宮殿"
Also called, "The sunken palace."
帶我們去那兒
Take us there.
他的話只會對應一樣東西
His words can only mean one thing.
沉沒的宮殿 地下水宮殿
Yerebatan Sarayi. The Sunken Palace.
咱們下去後 你就會看到了
Once we descend, you'll see exactly what he described.
這個怎麼用
How do I use it?
爆炸物裝在接線盒裡
There's a cap in the padial integrate.
爆炸裝置也有個引爆按鈕
The device also has a detonation button.
去個電話 就會引爆
A call from this cellphone will trigger the explosion.
這麼點就能弄破袋子嗎
And that's enough to break the bag?
四面牆壁都是混凝土
The walls are cement all around.
這倆炸彈都要裝上 兩個角度 盡量分開
You need both bombs, different angles, as far apart as you can.
然後就能弄破袋子
That's what break the bag.
史書認為黑死病帶來了苦難和死亡
History says that the Black Plague caused misery and death.
但並沒有告知我們
But, what they don't tell us,
它也同樣精簡了人口 並孕育了文藝復興運動
is that it also produced a leaner population, and gave birth to the Renaissance.
我們正在全速奔向地獄的第七層
We are rushing as fast as we can into the seventh circle of hell.
自取滅亡 卻又有利可圖
Suicidal but profitable.
能夠短痛 何必長痛
Why is suffering later preferable to suffering now?
倘若我們欣然接受 然後痛苦或許就能解救我們
What if we embrace it. And then maybe pain can save us.
你聽明白了 對吧 我看得出來
You're getting this, aren't you? I can see that you are.
現在我想知道的是我並非形單影隻
Now I need to know that I'm not alone.
人太特麼多了
Too many damn people.
地方選得很好
He has chosen well.
我需要所有進出蓄水池的管道分配圖
I need schematics of all conduits in and out of the cistern.
還有全面隔離和控制方案
Full isolation and containment protocols.
物理和化學屏蔽 外加... 等會
Physical and chemical barriers along with... Wait.
這是城內的供水系統嗎
This is the city's water supply?
噢 現在不是了 已經現代化改造過
Oh, not anymore. We've modernized.
但裡面的水就留在那兒
But there is water in there.
是的 最終慢慢滲入地下
Yes. It eventually filters down into the earth.
那為什麼這麼多人
But why are all these people here?
現在是旅遊景點了 那兒的演出很精彩
It is a tourist attraction. The acoustics are excellent.
今晚就有夏至音樂會 很受歡迎
Tonight is the summer solstice concert, very popular.
人們從世界各地趕來 欣賞盛會
People come from all over the world to hear it.
他製造了一種生物氣溶膠
He created a bioaerosol.
所以可以通過空氣傳播
So it will spread in the air.
- 清空現場人群
- 不要
- Empty the place. - No.
圍住那兒
Contain it.
屏蔽附近所有信號 斷絕信息進出
Jam all communications down there. No messages get in or out.
明白
Got it.
那我們進去吧
Shall we go in?
羅伯特 你不必陪我們進去
Robert, you don't have to go in there with us.
不 我要去的
Yes, I do.
"血紅的瀉湖不會倒映群星"
"Blood-red waters of the lagoon that reflects no stars."
老天爺 這兒就像個迷宮
My god, this is a labyrinth.
有多少塊區域
How many sections?
有很多 教授 很多
There are dozens, Professor, dozens.
我們去找到它
Let's find it.
檢查每個區域 每條柱子
Check every section, every column.
全要檢查
Check them all.
散開來
Spread out.
現在切斷手機信號
Cut off cellphone service now.
- 隔絕通訊
- 是長管
- No communications. - Yes, sir.
這兒有美國的聯絡人 我需要幫助
Those are US contacts over here, I need some help.
這裡 這邊走 美杜莎
Here. This way. Medusa.
美杜莎-是希臘 神話中的女蛇妖
希臘神話 為什麼
The Greek spirits, why?
它屬於希臘神話中的一個特定種類 地府鬼神
It belongs to a specific category of Greek spirits. Chthonic monsters.
- 就這兒嗎
- 是的
- This is it? - Yes.
顏色 柱子 跟視頻上看到的一模一樣
The color, the columns, it's exactly what we saw in the video
就是這兒了 大家散開 檢查柱子
This is the area, so spread out, check the pillars.
- 我負責牆邊
- 各個角落
- I'll take the wall line. - The corners.
走道下面
Under the walkway.
如有任何發現 立即向我報告
If you find anything, report to me immediately.
誰來照照這裡 分秒必爭
Light it here, someone. Seconds matter.
打擾一下 打擾一下
Excuse me. Excuse me.
- 發生什麼事了
- 先生請你讓開
- What's going on? - Sir, I need you to step aside.
各位請迴避
Step aside, everyone.
找著了 在這兒 那個角落裡
I got it. It's here. In this far corner.
重生
不要
Don't.
生化小組尚未就位
Hazmat guys aren't set yet.
我等不及了
I can't wait.
趕緊的 這玩意隨時會破
Quickly! This could break any moment.
西恩娜
Sienna!
這是氮氣吹洗裝置 徒手操作嗎
This is cube nitrogen purge. Without gloves access.
- 應該可以
- 最好如此
- It should. - It better.
西恩娜 西恩娜
Sienna. Sienna.
我們人多勢眾
There are too many of us down here!
你搶不到袋子的
You won't get to that bag before we do!
的確 但我會確保它破掉
No. But I can make sure it breaks.
不 別這麼做 西恩娜 不要 你會濫殺無辜
No. Don't do this, Sienna, don't. You'll be murdering innocents.
沒錯 很多人會死去
Yes. People will die
但危機得以避免
a lot of them but the crisis will be averted.
這是大自然的旨意
It's what nature demands.
人口危機問題不再只會緩解 而是一勞永逸的解決了
The problem won't just be slowed down, it would be solved permanently.
借生靈塗炭來拯救蒼生 這是暴君的邏輯
Killing billions to save lives. That's the logic of tyrants.
- 為了更高的目標人類．．．
- 就算天才也不能有這種權利
- For a greater good, humanity... - Geniuses don't come with extra rights.
不 他有責任去行他人所不能行之事
No, it comes with the responsibility to take action when others won't!
你想做點什麼 行啊
You want to do something, fine.
那就把問題提出來 然後解決掉
Then scream at the top of your lungs. An event and leave.
如果你愛這個物種 如果你愛這個星球
If you loved humanity, if you love this planet,
你會不惜一切去挽救它
you would do anything to save it.
人類歷史上那些極惡之罪都曾冠以愛的名義
The greatest sins in human history had been committed in the name of love.
但沒人會贊同這種看法
No one will look on this act and call it love.
人類會延續的
They'll be alive.
別人如何評價 又與我何干
What does it matter what they say about us.
無信號
No Signal
嘿 你在幹什麼
Hey, what are you doing?
不可以
Don't!
別射著箱子
Don't shoot the box!
羅伯特 快閃開
Robert, get clear!
你還好嗎 你沒事吧
Are you alright? Are you alright?
沒事
Fine.
箱子在哪 箱子在哪
Where's the box. Where's the box.
它密封了 完好無損
It's contained, no breach.
病毒已被完全隔離
The virus has been completely contained.
病毒已被隔離
The virus has been contained.
- 醫療小組全部進場
- 我們現在接管這兒的工作
- All medical team come in . - We'll take it from now on.
重複一遍 目標已被隔離 準備轉移
I repeat. The target is contained, be prepared for transport.
沒有洩漏 重複一遍 沒有洩漏
There is no leakage. I Repeat. There is no leakage.
她以為她在拯救世界
She thought she was saving the world.
他們也是這麼想的
So did they all.
那麼 接下來要做什麼
So, what would happen now?
我們會帶回日內瓦做檢測 把它隔離起來
We'll take it back to Geneva for test, put it in isolation.
首先要測出基因序列
We'll have to generate another geno sequences first
再順籐摸瓜 提出解決方案
to get an idea what we are dealing with.
接下來還有很多事要忙
There's a lot of work to be done.
你呢 回去嗎
And you, Cambridge?
是的
Yeah.
辛斯基博士
Dr. Sinskey?
生活又要把咱分開了
Life tore us apart again.
就像但丁和比阿特麗斯那樣
Like Dante and Beatrice.
我有東西要給你
I have something for you.
你被綁架那晚 我撿到了這個
I picked this up the night you were taken.
我記得它對你似乎意味非凡
I seem to remember it was important to you.
是的 是的沒錯
Yes. Yes, it is.
你有沒有想過 你我之間
Do you ever think about what could happen
會發生些什麼
with you and me?
我想過
I do.
我猜生活還得有點兒神秘感 教授
I guess life must have it's mysteries, Professor,
即便是我們倆
even for us.
佛羅倫薩 意大利
早上 9:00
- 打擾一下你會講英語嗎
- 會的
- ' Scusati, do you speak English? - Yes.
有沒有見到瑪塔·阿爾瓦雷茲 那位工作人員
Have you seen Marta Alvarez, the museum staff?
瑪塔現在不在這 她懷孕了
Marta isn't here just now. She's had her baby.
她懷孕了 啊呀 太棒了
She had her baby? Aw, that is great.
好消息
Great news.
那麼 你或許要通知某人該給但丁面具展位開燈了
Well, you might tell someone that the lights on the Dante mask
我幾乎看不到呢
should be turned on because I can barely see it.
我很遺憾 先生 但丁面具不在這兒
I'm sorry, sir, the Dante mask is no longer here.
它被盜了
It was stolen.
- 真的嗎 - 嗯 - 我剛還看著它呢
- Really? - Um - I was just looking at it.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
特效字幕
編譯製作
稚園老